<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance | Orlando Joaqui Barandica</title>
    <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/finance/</link>
      <atom:link href="www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Finance</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/www.joaquibarandica.io/media/logo_hu1789145b081cc5edb4bb9dabee2afbca_29678_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Finance</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/finance/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICEE 2022</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/icee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/icee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be at the ICEE 2022 – Energy and Environment: Uniting Economy and Engineering that will take place at the University of Porto, next June 2 and 3, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will present the research &amp;ldquo;Global liquidity and the profitability of energy firms&amp;rdquo;. This research is carried out in conjunction with, Professor Diego Manotas from the Universidad del Valle, and Professor Jorge M. Uribe from the Universidad Oberta de Cataluña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./porto2.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely a great academic adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./porto.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./porto3.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link for slides: &lt;a href=&#34;https://juniorjb5.github.io/ICEE2022/Presentation_ICEE_2022.html#1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;👉Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👋 All Comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; \&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminario CIEF - EAFIT</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/eafit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/eafit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next Wednesday (16/Feb/2022) I&amp;rsquo;ll present the conference &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ub.edu/irea/working_papers/2021/202113.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commonality, macroeconomic factors and bank profitability&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in the Seminario CIEF of the University EAFIT of Medellín - Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research was selected for presentation at the IFABS 2021 - Oxford conference &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joaquibarandica.com/project/ifabs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;(see more..)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the School of Economics and Finance for the invitation. Next, the information for the connection to the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link for registration: &lt;a href=&#34;http://s60148679.hs.eloqua.com/ReunionZoom-20210205&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;👉Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link for slides: &lt;a href=&#34;https://juniorjb5.github.io/EAFIT/Slides_EAFIT.html#1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;👉Here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Advances in Statistical Methods</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/sce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/sce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;distributed-lag-non-linear-models-dlnm-of-the-effect-of-macroeconomic-factors-on-the-msci-colombia-index-of-market-capitalization-in-the-stock-market-during-the-period-2001-to-2020&#34;&gt;Distributed lag non-linear models (DLNM) of the effect of macroeconomic factors on the MSCI Colombia index of market capitalization in the stock market during the period 2001 to 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is part of the thesis developed by students &lt;strong&gt;Brayan Osorio Vanegas&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Carolina Ramírez Patiño&lt;/strong&gt; from the academic program of Statistics at Universidad del Valle. On this occasion, we had the opportunity to participate in the advances in statistical workshop developed by the Colombian Statistics Society (SCE - &lt;em&gt;Sociedad Colombiana de Estadística&lt;/em&gt;), Inter American Statistical Institute, and National University of Colombia (UNAL - &lt;em&gt;Universidad Nacional de Colombia&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./SCE.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-download  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download &lt;a href=&#34;www.joaquibarandica.io/www.joaquibarandica.io/media/SCE_Ponencia.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes to study the external macroeconomic determinants on financial markets. Under the hypothesis of efficient markets, prices reflect all available information, so this paper will focus on the MSCI Colombia index, which measures the high and mid-capitalization segments of the stock market. The literature focuses on studying the macroeconomic effects at the variable level on the income market. However, from the statistical and econometric point of view, the possible omission of different effects associated with macroeconomic variables that are not considered in the different models in the literature is proposed, this shows a possible increase in the error of the estimates, which can generate biased estimates of macroeconomic movements on returns in the stock market. This is why a detailed analysis of the impact of the global set of macroeconomic variables on market capitalization is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, the generation of latent macroeconomic factors is proposed from a large set of variables, subsequently the macroeconomic factors are identified and interpreted to determine the effects in the terms of trade on the MSCI Colombia index. An extensive database is used, made up of 106 macroeconomic variables corresponding to the period 2001-2020, and the effect of macroeconomic shocks is estimated using a DLNM model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./SCE_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results show there are mainly three statistical factors that underlie the macroeconomic dynamics in Colombia. The results suggest that the first latent factor is associated with economic activity. The second factor is related to the external sector (imports, exports and exchange rate), and the third factor to the labor force and retail. We conclude that the effects are asymmetric on the rental market in addition to achieving stabilization of the shock after the third period. In addition, we identify that the market is more sensitive to economic activity compared to other macroeconomic factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./SCE_3.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👋 All Comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:osorio.brayan@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;osorio.brayan@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:carolina.ramirez.patino@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;carolina.ramirez.patino@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFABS 2021 - Oxford</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/ifabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/ifabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go to Oxford!👏 Yes, this time virtually but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, we will enjoy everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ub.edu/irea/working_papers/2021/202113.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commonality, macroeconomic factors and bank profitability&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; carried out with my advisers was selected for presentation at the IFABS 2021 - Oxford conference. The International Finance and Banking Society is a conference founded in 2008 in the UK, has become one of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading research networks dedicated to the promotion of cutting-edge research in the areas of Banking, Finance and FinTech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year due to the pandemic situation the event will be held virtually. In this version, the conference is organized in collaboration with Bank of Englad, King&amp;rsquo;s College London, University of Oxford and University of Nottingham on the general topic of the financial systems of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As keynote speakers will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry Summers, is a professor at Charles W. Eliot University and president emeritus of Harvard University. He served as President Clinton&amp;rsquo;s 71st Secretary of the Treasury and Director of President Obama&amp;rsquo;s National Economic Council.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claudia Buch, who joined the Bundesbank in 2014, is Vice President of the Deutsche Bundesbank and head of its Directorates-General for Financial Stability, Statistics and Internal Audit. She is a deputy of the central bank of the G20 and the G7 of the Bundesbank and a member of the Financial Stability Committee of Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willem Buiter is currently visiting professor of international and public affairs at Columbia University and an adjunct member of the Council on Foreign Relations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/1FMaabePDEfgk/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, could you imagine my happiness?😁😁😁 I don&amp;rsquo;t believe (and less, do you imagine my panic?😱😱😱), but like say my dad! &amp;ldquo;pa&#39; lante es pa&#39; lla&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
