<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electricity Prices | Orlando Joaqui Barandica</title>
    <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/electricity-prices/</link>
      <atom:link href="www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/electricity-prices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Electricity Prices</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/www.joaquibarandica.io/media/logo_hu1789145b081cc5edb4bb9dabee2afbca_29678_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Electricity Prices</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/tag/electricity-prices/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>9° ELAEE 2024</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/elaee9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/elaee9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;recent-contributions-at-the-9th-latin-american-meeting-on-energy-economics-elaee---rio-de-janeiro&#34;&gt;Recent Contributions at the 9th Latin American Meeting on Energy Economics (ELAEE) - Rio de Janeiro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportunity to present at the 9th Latin American Meeting on Energy Economics (ELAEE) held in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. This prestigious conference brought together leading experts and researchers in the field of energy economics to discuss the latest developments and challenges in the sector. I was fortunate to present two studies that contribute to the understanding of energy price dynamics and the impact of geopolitical factors on energy markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-assessment-of-energy-price-dynamics-a-gas-model-and-quantile-regression-analysis-between-natural-gas-climate-and-electricity-markets&#34;&gt;1. Assessment of Energy Price Dynamics: A GAS Model and Quantile Regression Analysis between Natural Gas, Climate, and Electricity Markets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study, developed in collaboration with Wilber Jr. Hernandez, Gina P. Ramirez, and Cesar A. Ojeda, explores the relationship between natural gas prices, climatic factors, and electricity markets using a GAS model and quantile regression analysis. The research aims to uncover the complex interactions between these variables, providing valuable insights into the dynamics of energy prices in volatile markets. The presentation focused on how fluctuations in natural gas prices, coupled with climate variability, impact electricity market prices, highlighting the importance of using advanced statistical models to better capture these relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👋 All Comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:orlando.joaqui@javerianacali.edu.co&#34;&gt;orlando.joaqui@javerianacali.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:cesar.ojeda@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;cesar.ojeda@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:gina.ramirez@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;gina.ramirez@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:wilber.hernandez@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;wilber.hernandez@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-armed-conflict-dynamics-and-energy-price-volatility-a-quantile-connectivity-approach&#34;&gt;2. Armed Conflict Dynamics and Energy Price Volatility: A Quantile Connectivity Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with Sebastián López-Estrada from Pontificia Universidad Javeriana de Cali, this paper investigates the impact of armed conflict dynamics on energy price volatility using a quantile connectivity approach. Our study provides a novel perspective on how geopolitical tensions and conflicts influence the behavior of energy prices, offering key insights into the interconnectedness of global energy markets. The findings underscore the need for robust analytical frameworks to understand the transmission of shocks across different segments of the energy sector, especially in times of political instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👋 All Comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sebastian.lopez@javerianacali.edu.co&#34;&gt;sebastian.lopez@javerianacali.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; \&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Advances in Statistical Methods</title>
      <link>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/sce2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>www.joaquibarandica.io/project/sce2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;modeling-the-effect-of-the-price-of-natural-gas-on-the-price-of-electricity-germany-in-times-of-distress&#34;&gt;Modeling the effect of the price of natural gas on the price of electricity: Germany in times of distress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is part of the thesis developed by students &lt;strong&gt;Wilber Jr. Hernandez&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Gina Paola Ramirez&lt;/strong&gt; from the academic program of Statistics at Universidad del Valle, under the joint direction of Professor &lt;strong&gt;César Ojeda&lt;/strong&gt; and myself. On this occasion, we had the opportunity to participate in the advances in statistical workshop developed by the Colombian Statistics Society (SCE - &lt;em&gt;Sociedad Colombiana de Estadística&lt;/em&gt;), and Universidad del Valle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./SCE.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-download  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download &lt;a href=&#34;www.joaquibarandica.io/www.joaquibarandica.io/media/SCE2_Ponencia.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes to observe the effect of the price of natural gas and the behavior of climatic factors on the price of electricity in times of crisis. At present it is known that Germany has increased the price of electricity due to complications for its production, which is produced by means of renewable and non-renewable energies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option being the most optimal since the cost is lower, however, they are not constant in the production flow due to the constant climatic changes, for which the electricity generated by non-renewable energies continues to have a large participation in Germany&amp;rsquo;s electricity matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, natural gas continues to be the fundamental pillar for the production of electricity, but it has been affected in recent years, due to the reduction in imports of natural gas of which Russia is its largest supplier, generated by the political discussions with Ukraine, through which various sanctions have been presented, of which the export of natural gas has been one of them. For this reason, it is proposed to observe the impact of the price of natural gas on the price of electricity in Germany during a period of time from 2015 to 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of GAS models is presented to observe the behavior of prices, the which allows a better adjustment of the data by having the versatility of working with distributions other than the normal distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./SCE_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results show: the price of natural gas presents a direct positive correlation with the price of electricity since if there is a shortage of natural gas as it occurred thanks to Russia&amp;rsquo;s problems with its exports, natural gas tends to increase its price and in turn the price of electricity respectively. In addition, climatic variables are important because they help to counteract the effect that the increase in the price of gas is producing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👋 All Comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;orlando.joaqui@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:cesar.ojeda@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;cesar.ojeda@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:gina.ramirez@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;gina.ramirez@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
📩 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:wilber.hernandez@correounivalle.edu.co&#34;&gt;wilber.hernandez@correounivalle.edu.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
